[Music]
[Música]
I'm wearing a fox cap, they're the
estoy con una gorra de zorro son las
new caps that the guy is making,
nuevas gorras que está haciendo [__]
man, I almost always forget, eh. We don't
tío casi siempre se me olvida eh No lo
mention it, but the fox thing, the store
mencionamos pero lo de zorro la tienda
has it here. Fran fenx Club,
la tiene aquí puesta Fran fenx Club
damn, I always forget and
[__] es que siempre se me olvida y
in fact, I can't forget
además de hecho no se me puede olvidar
that I wanted to put it in the
que lo quería poner yo en el en el
rewind at the end, the credits and well,
rewind al final los créditos y y bueno
the credits have to be
es que los créditos los tenemos que
completely fixed, the credits
arreglar por completo los créditos
because there are a lot of youtubers who
porque faltan un montón de youtubers que
do collaborate, okay, eh, but here you can
sí colaboran vale eh pero aquí podéis
buy the t-shirts and other things that you
comprar las camisetas y demás que muchas
often ask us about, not because of
veces nos preguntáis no por el tema de
the t-shirts and other things, and they are good
las camisetas y demás y y tienen buena
quality, eh, I have to, I have to order
calidad eh tengo que tengo que pedirme
some black sweatshirts. Well, one of each, I'm actually
unas sudaderas negras Bueno una de cada
going to order one of each,
me voy a pedir la verdad una de cada
but yeah, yeah, I like these, the
pero sí sí a mí me gustan estas la las
typical ones, okay, no, I don't like these that
típicas vale estas no estas no me gustan
much. I want the typical ones, these, these, I'm
tanto Yo quiero las típicas estas estas
going to order what else? What else do we
las voy a pedir qué más Qué má qué más
have here, fen Club, okay, you have it there, you have it
tenemos aquí fen Club vale por ahí lo
there, you can pay
tenéis por ahí lo tenéis podéis pagar
with PayPal with Google Pay, it's from fox, eh,
con PayPal con Google Pay es de zorro eh
the fox company, okay  you know how pretty
la empresa zorro vale que ya sabéis está
the cap is eh Hey, maybe I'll
guapa la gorra eh Oye por la gorra lo
get it too eh man you had to
mismo también me Pillo eh tío tenías que
do a raffle do you want me to do it
hacer un sorteo queréis que haga
talking about Fran's cap Look
hablando de la gorra de Fran Mira
WhatsApp we've been watching it Karime we've been watching it do you
WhatsApp lo hemos estado viendo Karime
want me to
lo hemos estado viendo que queréis que
get me to get a pack and we'll
me pille que me pille un pack y
raffle this thing off go there to the
sorteamos esta movida vais ahí al
website that says in the description of the
Website que pone en la descripción del
video about the fenex club and that's it what
vídeo lo del fenex club y ya está qué ha
happened what happened is that they've
pasado lo que ha pasado es que me han
filed a criminal complaint against me three
puesto una querella criminal tres
criminal complaints I'm going to explain it to you
querellas criminales os lo voy explicar
as soon as I arrive now the sanctuary which
en cuanto llegue ahora el santuario que
is here
est aquí
here
aquí
Capi is the east As soon as I get to the
Capi es el este En cuanto llegue al
sanctuary I'm going to sit down in the office and I'll
santuario me voy a sentar en la ofi y os
explain it to you they've filed three criminal complaints against me
lo explico me han puesto tres querellas
in one they're asking for jail they're asking for
criminales en una piden cárcel piden
deportation they're asking for money and I'm going to
deportación piden dinero y os voy a
explain clearly what it is and above
explicar claramente lo que es y sobre
all the collateral damage that it carries with it it
todo los daños colaterales que lleva
's a pain in the ass and I'm going to explain
encima es una putada y os voy a explicar
why three complaints why I
por qué tres querellas por qué me ha
got this complaint So nothing Look at
llegado esta querella Así que nada Mirad
what a beautiful sunset and right
qu puesta de sol tan bonita y justo
after seeing this sunset  of the sun from
después de ver esta puesta de sol desde
the sanctuary [ __ ] man, these
el santuario [__] tío que estas puestas
sunsets and all that, it's not that we don't see them here
de sol y demás no es que aquí no las
because they're different man let's watch the
vemos pues son diferentes tío vamos al
video guys let's watch the video how
vídeo chavales vamos al vídeo qué
different man Okay guys I'm already at
diferente tío Bueno chavales ya estoy en
the office what you see here this is the
la ofi esto que veis aquí esto es la
criminal complaint that they filed against me this is
querella criminal que me han puesto que
how they start Fran this is how they start with three
así empiezan Fran así empiezan con tres
complaints well it starts off slow a
querellas bueno empieza flojito un
bunch of papers it has the stamp the
montón de papeles tiene con el sello
whole story I don't want to show it
toda la historia no lo quiero enseñar
because it's legal to show all those
porque no Es legal enseñar todos esos
official stamps but
sellos oficiales pero me ha llegado hace
a couple of days ago I received a criminal complaint
un par de días una querella criminal
as I told you at the beginning of the video
como os he dicho al principio del vídeo
What is a criminal complaint well it's
Qué es una querella criminal pues es
something that someone files against you because they want you to
algo que alguien te pone porque quiere
go to jail or if you're a
que vayas a la cárcel o si eres un
foreigner they want you deported in
extranjero quiere que te deporten en
this country no
este país no
Ah it's three complaints in one and all this
Ah son tres quellas en una y todo esto
sorry are you vaping grandpa no
perdonad estás vapeando abuelo no
georgio I was doing cocaine all
georgio me estaba metiendo cocaína todo
this started to take shape on
esto se empezó a fraguar el día 13 de
November 13th which is why my suspicions
noviembre con lo cual mis sospechas
when immigration came
cuando vino inmigración vinieron los de
these people came the police to the others my
estos los policías a los otros mis
suspicions were not unfounded And although
sospechas no eran infundadas Y aunque
I officially said that well no  you guys are going to cause
dije oficialmente que bueno no vayáis a
trouble don't say anything because no one
meter [__] no digáis nada porque no se
knows who it belongs to I already had a hunch who it
sabe de quién es Yo ya me olía de quién
came from even the animal police
venía incluso la policía animal me
warned me and said Hey This is going to happen I
advirtió y me dijo Eh Esto va a pasar Yo
didn't think they were going to go that far
tampoco pensé que fueran a ir tan allá
but anyway they've filed a criminal complaint against me
pero bueno me han puesto una querella
three in one eh the cu Ah well that's
criminal tres en una eh las cu Ah bueno
better than vaping Javi yes fact
es mejor eso que vapear Javi sí facto
are to destroy me okay This
son para destruirme de acuerdo Esto no
is not a complaint that has been filed to
es una querella que se haya puesto para
win something or to clear a name
ganar al algo o para limpiar un nombre
like they say or it hasn't been to
como dicen o para no ha sido para
destroy me destroy me destroy the
destruirme destruirme a mí destruir el
sanctuary and as collateral damage to
santuario y como daño colateral a
harming zorro I'm going to explain to you
hacerle daño a zorro os voy a explicar
slowly and without much trouble and without
despacito y sin mucho problema y sin
much history How this works well
mucha historia Cómo funciona esto bien
here there are three complaints the first is eh
aquí hay tres denuncias la primera es eh
For like a kind of right to honor
Por como una especie de derecho al honor
that is not the right to honor eh she is
que no es derecho al honor eh está
reporting that because of me and for having
denunciando que por mi culpa y por haber
made a campaign against her eh her
hecho una campaña contra ella eh su
image has deteriorated eh I have torn
imagen se ha deteriorado eh he trozado
her public image to pieces let's see the issue of the
su imagen pública a ver el tema del
right to honor and both here in Spain and
derecho al honor e tanto aquí en España
in almost all countries in the
como en casi todos los países em el
right to honor is not that or is the
derecho al honor no es que o sea el
right to honor  is that you have damaged
derecho al honor es que tú hayas dañado
the image of that person or rather the
la imagen de esa persona o sea el
right to honor in the end it is something very
derecho al honor al final es algo muy
subjective at the time of the Judge in which it
subjetivo a la hora del Juez en el que
falls eh because we have seen cases in which
caiga eh porque hemos visto casos en los
suddenly an atrocity is not
que de repente una barbaridad no se
condemned and a stupid thing is condemned
condena y una tontería sí se condena
okay eh of course when we talk about
vale eh claro cuando hablamos de
condemning it does not mean that condemning and it
condenar no significa que condenar e no
is not all black or white okay for example
es todo blanco o negro vale por ejemplo
to me eh in the sentence that
a mí e eh en la condena esta que me
they gave me Of course they condemned because they
pusieron Claro condenaban porque
condemned to delete the videos you
condenaban a borrar los vídeos me
understand they were not going to make me pay
entiendes no me iban a hacer pagar
80,000 euros as the colleague asked no but it
80,000 eur como pedía el colega no sino
was Look yes remove the videos Because
que era Mira sí quitar los vídeos Porque
these videos are more disproportionate I don't
estos vídeos son más desproporcionados
know what I don't know how much they are worth they are there they
no sé qué no sé cuánto vale están ahí
damage the image of this person but you
dañan la imagen de esta persona pero
also have to take into account that the
también tié que tener en cuenta que el
right to honor is often
derecho al honor muchas veces la gente
taken as e Of course that
se lo toma como
[ __ ] it is that it is very
e Claro que que [__] es que es muy
relative man it is very relative because that is what it
relativo tío es muy relativo porque es
has to be that it damages your image
lo que tiene que ser que dañe tu imagen
that it damages your reputation that it changes the
que dañe tu reputación que cambie la
perception Maybe of the of the of what
percepción A lo mejor de la de la de lo
people have of the image that people have of
que la gente tiene de la imagen que
you not the  that you
tiene la gente sobre ti no la que tú
would like to have, I don't know the truth is that it's a
quisieras tener no sé la verdad es un
bit of a problem eh But well here in Asia apparently the issue of the right to honor is very penalized it's a thing there in Asia as such in general not only in Thailand that is taken very seriously and
Tailandia que que se toma muy en serio y
that is not able to get the
que no es capaz de conseguir los
jobs that you want or something like that no
trabajos que quiere o una cosa así no
that later I also tell you eh about
que después también te digo eh lo de
Fran what about Yuji what Fran talked about this is
Fran lo de yuji lo que Fran habló esto
talked about in was talked about in Spain or rather in
se habla en se habló en España o sea en
Thailand This was not talked about that he is
Tailandia Esto no se habló que está
looking for promotions sponsors Yuji
buscando promociones patrocinadores yuji
in Thailand or rather in Spain no
en en Tailandia o sea en España no
because in any case the bad image of
porque en todo caso la imagen mala de
Yui is in Spain eh I don't know if
yui la tiene en España eh yo no sé si
Well I know what is going to be fought it is going to have to be
Bueno yo sé lo que se va a pelear va a
fought but that is one of
haber que pelearlo pero eso es una de
the complaints that has lost
las denuncias que ha perdido
credibility and Image here in
credibilidad e e Imagen aquí en
Thailand because well I don't know the truth
Tailandia porque pues no sé la verdad
okay because here here nothing is said
vale porque aquí de aquí no se habla
about all of that nor has it been talked about well that
nada de de todo eso ni se hablado bueno
is the first the second is to
esa es la primera la segunda es para
say that I did some Kick live shows
decir que yo hice unos directos de Kick
in which I asked for money to
en los los cuales pedí dinero para que
come illegally to Thailand because I
viniera ilegalmente a Tailandia porque
don't have a specific work permit
no tengo un permiso de trabajo
for kik and also that I am
específico para kik y también que estoy
making YouTube videos in which I'm
haciendo vídeos de YouTube en los cuales
abusing animals eh And I don't
estoy abusando de los animales eh Y no
have a specific
tengo un un permiso específico de
work permit for YouTube okay specific
trabajo para YouTube vale específico de
okay Ah that would be the second
acuerdo Ah esa sería la segunda delito
tax offense eh third that I have
fiscal eh tercera que tengo animales
protected animals inside the sanctuary in poor
protegidos dentro del santuario en mal
condition that I'm using to
estado que los estoy utilizando para
make the videos and that I've set up
hacer los vídeos y que me he montado
a place here in which I have eh
aquí un zo en el cual tengo eh animales
illegal animals okay it's the authorities
ilegales de acuerdo son las autoridades
that call him to collect
las que lo llaman a él para que recojan
the animals Those are the three complaints
los animales Esas son las tres denuncias
that he has filed against me criminals it costs a
que me ha puesto criminales cuesta una
fortune to do that here eh and what does this
pasta aquí hacer eso eh e Y esto qué
mean does this mean that I can
quiere decir esto quiere decir que puedo
go to jail They can deport me and
ir a la cárcel Me pueden deportar y
apart from that they can impose a big fine you
aparte de pueden poner una multa gorda
can win you can win I'll
se puede ganar se puede ganar yo os
explain eh I've been doing what I don't know I mean I hear
explico eh hace yo que no sé o sea yo
Fran was already telling me this
heo ya me me lo vino contando Fran hace
days ago Eh and I didn't know that he was going to upload
días Eh e yo no sabía que iba a subir él
a video so quickly I mean eh he had
un vídeo tan rápido o sea eh él me lo
been telling me this for days at first he
venía contando hace día en principio él
had a decision made which was
tenía una decisión tomada que era
basically to leave Thailand or
básicamente pues irse de Tailandia o
something like that okay but but
algo por el estilo vale pero pero
finally he surprised me the other day
finalmente me sorprende el otro día
when we were on the live show he
cuando estábamos en el directo que me
said no no  Hey I'm going to fight it eh I don't know
dice no no Oye lo voy a pelear eh No sé
if you noticed at the end of the
si os disteis cuenta al final del
live more or less when he's making a
directo más o menos cuando está haciendo
sandwich eh He says to me Well I don't know what of
sándwich eh Me dice Bueno no sé qué
course and he already told me last night like he was going to
claro y ya me dijo anoche como que iba a
make a video all the r but I didn't
hacer un vídeo todo el r ese pero no
know he was going to do it so fast two
sabía que lo iba a hacer tan rápido dos
days ago I spoke with a lawyer he wasn't a
días hablé con con un abogado no era
criminal lawyer and he said what about you don't
penalista y me dijo que tal no le
ask your husband cru I imagine that he
preguntarás a tuyupa cru me imagino que
must have spoken with your husband in the end it's his
habrá hablado con tuyupa a él al final
issue you know what I mean I
es un tema de él me entiendes o sea yo
'm here to help him in whatever way I can which is
estoy aquí para ayudarle en lo que esté
almost nothing the
en mi mano que es pues casi nada la
truth is more than giving him moral and
verdad más que darle apoyo moral y
emotional support and such you know I mean
emocional y y tal me entiendes O sea que
here I can't do anything it's not like we
aquí no puedo hacer yo nada no es como
can do a 24 hour live you
que podamos hacer un directo de 24 horas
know and the way he saw it I
me entiendes y como lo veía él ya me
could leave Thailand before
podía ir de Tailandia antes de que
the process started because they were going to
empezara el proceso porque me iban a
charge me because I was going to end up in
empapelar porque iba a terminar en la
jail What they're basically asking for is to
cárcel Lo que están pidiendo básicamente
beat me up okay Oh and
es que es machacarme de acuerdo Ah y yo
the truth is I thought I say Well if you
la verdad es que pensé digo Bueno si te
leave Thailand you start
vas de Tailandia te empiezas en otro
somewhere else but I have  Once this sanctuary was set up,
sitio pero yo he montado este santuario
what I personally told him was to
yo personalmente lo que le dije fue que
leave Thailand. Okay, let them
se fuera de Tailandia vale que las
sell the land. Let these people sell it
tierras las vendan las vendan esta gente
when they can. You know, in the end, that
cuando puedan sabes o sea al final eso
has an enormous economic value, it's already
tiene un valor económico enorme ya son
theirs and the whole thing about the son. Don't
suyas y todo el rollo del hijo no que lo
sell it. Sell everything. Let him find a
vendan que lo vendan todo que busque la
way to do it. The animals, but
manera de hacer los animales pero es que
the thing is, the thing is that with that
a ver el tema es que el tema es que esa
option, the animals are left abandoned. Of
opción los animales los dej abandonados
course, but let's see if they're going to put you in
Claro pero a ver si te van a meter en la
jail, of course. The thing is that, but of course,
cárcel claro el tema es que eso pero
if they're going to put you in jail, you
claro es que si te van a meter en la
'll have to leave. I mean, if they're going to
cárcel tendrás que irte no O sea si te
deport you. Anyway, no. Or they're going to put you on
van a deportar Igualmente no O te van a
ice. They're going to deport you. Anyway,
meter acelo te van a deportar Igualmente
what the hell are you doing with the animals? What the hell are you
qué [__] haces con los animales qué [__]
doing with all the ostriches? It's a
haces con todas las avest truces es una
mess, eh. But man, I understand that there will
movida eso eh pero hombre entiendo que
be an organization. I don't know what the
habrá un organ No sé lo que harían los
animals would do. Honestly, I don't know what they would do. I don't
animales la verdad no sé lo que harían
know what they would do. But of course, what I
no sé lo que harían pero claro yo lo que
told him was, look, Juan Luis Mal Partida, what
le dije fue Mira Juan Luis malpartida
are you doing with? I go almost every
que es a yo voy casi todos los fines de
weekend to see Juan Luis Mal Partida.
semana a ver a Juan Luis mal partida
Juan Luis Mal Partida has set up.  here
Juan Luis mal partida tiene montado aquí
in
en
Seville your shelter okay I go
Sevilla el refugio suyo vale Yo voy a
see him every weekend because you
verlo todos los fines de semana porque
know what Leo is like okay one day I'm going to
ya sabéis Cómo es Leo vale un día voy a
do a one day I'm going to do a
haceros un un día voy a haceros un
report where Juan
reportaje donde Juan le
and he looks This was the other day Oh look
y él mira Esto fue el otro día Ah mira
two years ago Okay well the other day he
hace dos años Vale pues el otro día él
does the same thing he has an area where
hace igual él tiene una zona donde están
the wolves are and he goes there for a while he
los lobos y él se va para allá un ratito
takes his walk with the wolves anyway in the
se pega su paseo con Los Lobos sea al
end they are animals just like Fran But
final son animales igual que Fran Pero
this Yes it smells bad by point what
esto Sí huele feo por punto lo que
you experienced with Daniel Sancho do you think c
viviste de Daniel Sancho crees c la
justice is not so manipulative dagger poor
justicia no es tan manip puñal pobre
Frank better to stay single Dante
Frank mejor quedarse soltero Dante yo a
not to me when Fran told me I see him
mí no cuando me lo contó Fran yo lo veo
weak Well now he's going to keep talking
flojo Bueno ahora va a seguir hablando
I see him weak the truth I mean I do
yo lo veo flojo la verdad o sea es que
n't know that you're going to go to jail
no sé que te vas a meter en la cárcel
for this see yes I know that I know that the issue
por esto ver sí sé que sí sé que el tema
of honor can be very complicated in
del honor sí puede ser muy [__] en
Spain and we would have to review
España y tendríamos que revisar a lo
maybe but of course what Frank could have said
mejor pero claro qué qué ha podido decir
that violates Yuji's honor about
Frank que vulnere el honor de yuji lo de
the drugs has she told him or I mean if
la droga se le ha contado ella o sea si
Fran already responded because she  said
Fran ya respondió porque ella lo contó
Fran was lying to protect her that I
Fran estaba mintiendo por protegerla que
also imagine that he will use it
eso también me imagino que lo utilizará
in his defense no I mean but if I was
en su defensa no O sea pero si yo estaba
I was lying in all the in
yo estaba mintiendo en todos los en
all the programs on the planet to
todos los programas del planeta para
defend her I mean I said that they were
defenderla O sea yo dije que la estaban
unfairly putting her in jail there
metiendo injustamente en la cárcel ahí
the truth has come out Now the truth It came out
ya salió la verdad Ahora la verdad Salió
now because she told it in a
ahora porque ella lo contó en un
program before him or so what
programa antes que él o sea qué es lo
can come out that I don't know I hope
que puede salir que no no sé yo espero
he wins I don't know the truth I hope
que lo gane no sé la verdad yo espero
he wins the issue the issue of
que lo gane el tema el tema de lo de la
regularity with with making content
regularidad con con con hacer contenido
I imagine that Fran will have it more than
me imagino que lo tendrá Fran más que
solved with the time that the
solucionado con la de tiempo que la de
years that he has been making content I mean
años que lleva haciendo contenido o sea
how many years has Fran been making
cuántos años tiene Fran haciendo
content he will have that more than not and
contenido lo tendrá eso ya más que no y
then what was the other thing Ah the thing about the
luego queé era lo otro Ah lo de los
animals well it's as simple as
animales pues es tan sencillo como
visualizing that there is no animal abuse no I don't
visualizar que no hay maltrato animal no
know but well this I would have
no sé pero bueno esto yo me hubiera
come to Spain buy a piece of land
venido para España compro un terreno
okay And look Juan Luis in the end has the
vale Y mira Juan Luis al final tiene lo
same thing I mean it's the same they are animals that
mismo o sea es lo mismo son animales que
for whatever reason they have tried to
por lo que sean los han intentado
trick them I don't know what And he goes and
trapichear No sé qué Y él los va los
picks them up I mean he picks them up and  and they are
recoge o sea él los recoge y y son
animals that are raised there with it it's
animales que se crían allí con él es
like a sanctuary or rather what
como un santuario o sea en verdad lo que
happens is that it has the part where you
pasa que tiene la parte en la que tú
can visit that is not the whole thing it's
pues puedes visitar que no es toda es
a zoological part let's not say no that I
una parte zoológica no digamos no que me
imagine it will be to finance itself I have been
imagino que será para financiarse yo
living in Thailand for 27 years I have
llevo 27 años viviendo en Tailandia no
never had any legal problems I have not
he tenido nunca ningún problema legal no
had any problems of any kind
he tenido ningún problema de ningún tipo
in that sense and I have set up this
en ese sentido y yo he montado este
sanctuary so that the animals that
santuario para que los animales que
were in terrible conditions or are
estaban en unas condiciones pésimas o
going to have terrible
van a tener unas condiciones pésimas de
living conditions can have a second
vida puedan tener una segunda
chance to be animals I am not going
oportunidad de ser animales yo no me voy
to leave here until they kick me out or until they
a ir de aquí hasta que me echen o hasta
put me in jail and I can't
que me metan en la cárcel y no pueda
take care of them okay I know that what they
cuidarlos de acuerdo sé que lo que
want is Eh Well that I don't have
quieren es Eh Pues eso que no tenga
any permit that they take away from me thanks
ningún permiso que me quiten gracias
Solange who wakes up well who
solange que se despierta bueno que se
wakes up of course What are you doing here
despierta claro Qué haces aquí a esta
now I wasn't expecting you Thank you so much
ahora que no te esperaba Muchísimas
Solange you are always
gracias solange siempre nos está
supporting us with all the content Solange
apoyando todos los contenidos solange
both in the primary,
tanto en el principal como en el
secondary, tertiary and
secundario como en el terciario como en
quintary a kiss beautiful
el quintario un beso guapísima
Thank you so much sweetheart in everything and  that they take my
Muchísimas gracias corazón en todo y que
animals away, that's what they
me saquen los animales eso es lo que
're looking for because they do harm in that
están buscando porque hacen daño de esa
way, it's a very tricky complaint, it's a
manera es una denuncia muy tricky es una
complaint that I will now explain to you, why it's
denuncia que ahora os explicaré Por qué
going to backfire a lot,
se va a volver en contra y mucho
and the YouTube issue, the issue of such and such, she also does
y y el tema de YouTube el tema de tal
n't realize that that money
tampoco se da cuenta de que ese dinero
was because because as I would define it,
era porque porque como yo le definira un
blackmail, I mean, eh, if I wanted her to
chantaje es decir eh si yo quería que
put the land in her children's name, Ah,
pusiera la tierra nombre de sus hijos Ah
It's true, of course, I mean, if
Es verdad claro o sea si el dinero lo ha
she earned the money, what the [ __ ] is wrong with her, what the [ __ ] is she
ganado ella qué [__] le van qué [__] le
claiming from him because he worked
está reclamando a él porque ha trabajado
without, without regulating, if the money
sin sin regular si el dinero se ha
stayed with her or in the name of her
quedado ella o a nombre de zorro de su
son's fox, she had to pay him money, she had to
hijo tenía que pagarle un dinero tenía
buy back the sanctuary, well, that will be
que recomprar el santuario bien eso se
fought, it will be fought. But those are the three
luchará se peleará Pero eso son las tres
complaints that she has filed, I know that from
querellas que ha puesto sé que desde
Europe it looks stupid and absurd. Yes, I
Europa se ve estúpido y absurdo Sí yo
totally see it. Of course, I'm telling you, let's
totalmente lo veo Claro ya te digo sea
see, we're not there, eh, in California, it's
ver no estamos allí eh en California son
5:00 p.m., that is, in the afternoon, sun. Angel.
las 5 las 6 o sea de la tarde sol Angel
Well, a kiss for California, Javi, do you think it is
Pues un beso para California Javi crees
possible to request
que se puede solicitar al gobierno de
protection from the Thai government for Fran and the
Tailandia protección a Fran y al
sanctuary? I have no idea, he
santuario Es que no tengo ni idea eso ya
'll say that.  Fran will probably
lo irá diciendo Fran de alguna manera ya
come up here someday Fran will probably
subirá por aquí Fran seguramente estos
come up here someday or we'll talk about it on
días subirá algún día o lo hablaremos el
Sunday we'll talk about it on Sunday
domingo lo hablaremos el domingo
for sure but I don't know it's clear I
seguramente pero no sé es que claro yo
see it and that's what he says it
lo veo y es lo que es lo que él dice a
seems stupid to me but why
mí me parece estúpido pero por qué
Because I live here but it's that
Porque yo vivo aquí pero es que ya la la
justice in Asia I mean no it can't be
justicia en Asia O sea no no se puede
compared We've already seen it I mean it can't be
comparar Ya lo hemos visto O sea no se
compared it can't be compared I mean
puede comparar no se puede comparar o
here what I see well here
sea yo aquí que lo que veo pues que aquí
what right to honor No what the [ __ ]
que qué derecho al honor No qué [__]
are things that she herself has commented on in
son cosas que ella misma ha comentado en
the case that there was some insult in
el caso que hubiera algún insulto en
any of Frank's live shows that
alguno de los directos de Frank que
right now I don't remember well
ahora mismo de memoria lo desconozco
a fine no and and the issue of regulating
pues una multa no y y el tema de regular
here for example in Spain when you
aquí por ejemplo en España cuando tú
do something irregular in terms of taxes the
haces algo irregular de tema impuesto
Treasury what it does is ask you for the
Hacienda lo que hace es pedirte el
money and maybe with interest with a
dinero y a lo mejor con intereses con un
little bit of interest Maybe eh
poquito de intereses A lo mejor eh
Because most of the time it's an
Porque la mayoría de las veces es
agreement so that you pay and outside eh you
acuerdo para que tú pagues y fuera eh
know I can't think of a way that
sabes que no se me ocurre la manera de
here in Spain they would put you in
que aquí en España te metieran en la
jail for something like that you know and it's not like
cárcel por algo así sabes y ni es que ni
even if they sentenced you to prison  they would
aunque te condenaran a prisión te
condemn him to something so that you end up in
condenarían a algo para que llegues a
jail you know the thing is
pis a la cárcel me entiendes el tema es
that here here in Thailand For example
que aquí aquí en Tailandia Por ejemplo
if they sentence him to prison he goes
si le condenan a prisión él va de
to prison right away you know the [ __ ] look
momento a la prisión sabes [__] fijaros
at Yuji not with Yuji yes it's true that
con yuji no con yuji sí es verdad que
she eh Yes it's true that she had eh drugs
ella eh Sí es verdad que tenía eh droga
s It's true that she had that problem but
s Es verdad que tenía ese problema pero
but not drug trafficking How was what they
pero no un tráfico de droga Cómo era lo
put her in no and it took her 6 years to
que le metieron no y le costó 6 años
get her acquitted in the end because of course it
sacarla absuelta al final porque claro
was her own consumption
era un consumo propio
So then what I'm telling you I don't know
Entonces entonces lo que te digo no sé
what can happen the truth is he he's
qué puede pasar la verdad él él está
worried he thinks that they can
preocupado él cree que que le pueden
put him in jail and then I'll have to
meter la cárcel y luego tendré que
fight it you know and America will also look
pelearlo sabes y América también se verá
stupid absurd but here the laws
estúpido de absurdo pero aquí las leyes
work differently the courts
funcionan de otra manera los juzgados
work differently and here if you
funcionan de otra manera y aquí como
have eh affinity and above all a lot of
tengas eh afinidad y sobre todo mucho
money it can work in
dinero puede llegar a funcionar de
some different way okay
alguna manera diferente vale
especially in a case that is neither
especialmente en un caso que no es ni de
blood nor hard drugs nor this
sangre ni de drogas fuertes ni de esto
nor that no eh what can happen to me well There
ni lo otro no eh qué me puede pasar pues
are sentences of up to 5 years that they can
Hay penas de hasta 5 años que me pueden
put me in jail and stipulated by law
meter de cárcel e estipulado por la ley
what are they accusing me of Well all the  crimes
qué me imputan Pues todos los delitos
that I've told you and what's the problem here
que os he dicho y cuál es la putada aquí
that they don't think about
que ellos no piensan en los daños
collateral damage in any way the owner
colaterales de ninguna manera el dueño
of the land is a fox if they
de la tierra es zorro si a mí me
condemn me for a crime they condemn the fox
condenan por un delito a zorro le
he is the owner of the land he
condenan él es el dueño de la tierra él
is the one who theoretically is letting me
es el que teóricamente me está dejando
here commit crimes according to his mother with
aquí cometer delitos según su madre con
which he is an accomplice to a crime with which
lo cual es cómplice de un delito con lo
an investigation would automatically be opened eh
cual se abriría automáticamente eh una
on him also that is to say
instrucción sobre él también es decir
that they have not thought about that why because
que no han pensado en eso por qué Porque
he is going to go to testify too
él va a ir a declarar también
Surely zape will come from Spain to
Seguramente zape se venga desde España a
testify And surely his daughter who is
declarar Y seguramente su hija que tiene
really pissed off eh Also
un cabreo de la [__] eh También
ends up testifying even though she is a minor
termine declarando aunque sea menor por
why because this is done to cause harm
qué porque esto se hace para hacer daño
It will be explained in the trial eh
Ya se explicará en el juicio eh las
things but if theoretically it has damaged his
cosas pero si teóricamente ha dañado su
image what image in Spain in
imagen qué imagen en España en
South America in Russia in the United States
Sudamérica en Rusia en Estados Unidos
which is where more or less people see me
que es donde más o menos la gente me ve
Central America North America where in
Centroamérica Norteamérica dónde en
Thailand in Thailand they don't even know the
Tailandia en Tailandia no saben ni ni la
month to the half eh that I committed a crime
mes a la media eh que yo cometí delito
with the kik issue and that I talked
con el tema de kik y que yo hablaba
[ __ ] about her and that I got money
[__] de ella y que conseguí dinero a
by talking bad about  her No, I didn't
base de hablar mal de ella No yo no
speak badly of her, I said what was
hablé mal de ella yo dije lo que estaba
happening and why we were asking for
pasando y por qué estábamos pidiendo
donations to pay her. In fact,
donaciones para pagarle a ella de hecho
all that money was for her. She's asking for
todo ese dinero fue para ella que pide
damages for such. Well, it's
daños y perjuicios por tal Pues bueno
been proven that I've given her more than
probado está que yo le he dado más de
250,000 in the last 2 years,
250,000 en los últimos 2 años
of course, you fool, I feel you, fool, I mean,
claro tonto yo ti senti tonto yo O sea
what money are you going to ask her for, of course, eh?
si qué dinero Le vas a pedir claro eh
For example, well, this is criminal, I don't
Por ejemplo bueno Esto que es penal no
understand, no, but here in Spain a
entiendo no pero aquí en España una
civil lawsuit, a civil lawsuit is because
civil una demanda civil es porque
someone considers that another person
alguien considera que otra persona le
owes them money, no, for example, these lawsuits are
debe dinero no por ejemplo las demandas
for the right to honor, you don't owe me
estas por derecho a honor no me debes
money for the damage that you have done to my
dinero por el daño que has hecho a mi
image, earning money, eh, what is she
imagen ganando dinero no eh qué está
claiming? No, based on what, she took the
reclamando no que en base a qué si el
money from all these acts, I
dinero de todos estos actos se lo ha
mean, there is no profit. At
llevado ella o sea no hay un lucro que
Christmas, talking to my children, I
navidades hablando con mis hijos les
was nagging them so that they
estuve dando el [__] para que
would be with their mother, so that they would
estuvieran con su madre para que
try to smooth out their laziness, eh, I got them to
intentaran limar as perezas eh conseguí
go to lunch on Christmas Day,
que fueran a comer el día de Navidad a
to go to lunch with her, after
que fueran a comer con ella después de
Christmas Eve the next day, to go to
Nochebuena al día siguiente que fueran a
lunch with her a few days ago, zen wanted
comer con ella hace unos días zen quería
be with his dog so and so I let him
estar con su perro tal y cual le dejé
go with his mother or so I told him
que fuera con su madre o tad é le dije
well Hey stay with your mother for a few days
pues Oye quédate con tu madre unos días
I told you a long time ago until I
yo os lo dije hace tiempo hasta que no
leave Thailand they won't rest
me vaya de Tailandia no van a descansar
what happens is that this is going to turn
lo que pasa es que esto se va a volver
against me I could lose one of those
en contra Yo puedo perder alguno de esos
three cases I will surely lose one
tres casos seguramente pierda alguno
surely something will happen I know I know or maybe all
seguramente algo pase lo sé lo sé o a lo
three and I'll end up Well that a year
mejor los tres y termino Pues eso un año
in jail or two or deported or
en la cárcel o dos o dep portado o lo
whatever then So I wanted to explain
que sea entonces Entonces era explicaros
that to you eh what hurts me the most Is that fox is
eso eh lo que más me duele Es que zorro
going to get one because Obviously the
se va a llevar una porque Obviamente el
lawyer said let's see if she wanted you to
abogado ha dicho a ver si ella quería
make a contract for the site
que hicieras un contrato de la del sitio
or I mean it's that I had to sign a
o sea es que yo le tuve que firmar un
contract do you remember rent so
contrato os acordáis de alquiler para
that if something happened she wouldn't have
que si pasaba algo ella no tuviera
any charges or anything or anything How
ninguna imputación ni nada ni tal Qué
strong this eh I mean the reason why
fuerte esto eh o sea el motivo por el
she had eh the sanctuary was because of
que ella tenía eh el santuario era por
the issue that he couldn't have it not in
el tema de que él no podía tenerlo no a
his name but uh yes they had a
su nombre pero Eh sí que tenían un
rental contract in the last few years
contrato de alquiler en los últimos años
for Well I don't know if years or months I think a
por Bueno no sé si años o meses creo que
year and a half maybe  or two years because of the
año y pico a lo mejor o dos años por el
issue that there was
tema de que hubiera una responsabilidad
only his responsibility for what was happening
solo en él de lo que estaba pasando
inside the sanctuary And then she
dentro del santuario Y entonces ella
to get rid of her hands in case
para librarse de las manos por si pasaba
something happened inside the sanctuary that was not
algo dentro del santuario que no fuera
her responsibility has done the same thing
responsabilidad suya ha hecho lo mismo
now with her son this is tremendous And that this
ahora con su hijo esto es tremendo Y esa
is tremendous that complaint that she
esto es tremendo esa denuncia que ella
feared they would file against her for being the
temía que le pusieran a ella por ser la
owner of the land has been filed by
propietaria de la tierra la ha puesto
her now the same one that she was
ella ahora la misma de la que ella tenía
afraid they would file against her when she was the
miedo que le pusieran cuando ella era la
owner of the land What does it mean that
duea en la tierra Qué quiere decir que
here at the moment that the
aquí en el momento que esté la
investigation is further along, then zorro is going to
investigación más adelante pues zorro va
have a problem because he is the
a tener un problema porque él es el
owner of the land and he is with me
dueño de la tierra y él está conmigo
here He is here with me he is part of the
aquí Él está aquí conmigo es parte del
sanctuary eh And I will not go through that anymore so
santuario eh Y eso eso ya no lo paso
know that they are going to be
entonces que sepáis que van a ser meses
hard months I was telling you the other day that you have to
duros os decía el otro día que hay que
be happy every day hard months
estar feliz todos los días meses duros
because on March 6th I have to go
porque el día 6 de marzo yo tengo que ir
to court they are going to read the
al juzgado me van a leer las
charges to me and I am going to have about three months
imputaciones y voy a tener unos TR meses
more or less with the lawyer to
más o menos con el abogado para
answer all those charges and I
contestar a todas esas imputaciones y ya
tell you in the best of  the cases fall
os digo en el mejor de los casos me cae
a little but something is going to fall on me because it is
un poco pero algo me va a caer porque
very well prepared they have had
está muy bien preparada han tenido
many months eh to prepare this
muchos meses eh para preparar esto
eh remember that here The police already came
eh acordaros que aquí Ya vino la policía
Once immigration came they came such and such they have been for
Una vez vino inmigración vino tal llevan
many months they have been since November
muchos meses llevan desde noviembre
since October preparing it and since
desde octubre preparándolo y desde
November the complaint was filed and
noviembre que se puso la querella y
now after the
ahora pues ya después de las
investigations that the
investigaciones que ha hecho la policía
immigration police have done everything that had
inmigración todo aquello que había
happened Well now a couple of days ago
pasado Pues ahora ya hace un par de días
I received eh That no action with
me ha llegado eh Esa no ación con toda
the entire complaint and on March 6th the judge will
la querella y el día 6 de marzo el juez
read me the charges and I will have Well
me leerá las imputaciones y tendré Pues
that three months or two months or a month to be
eso tres meses o dos meses o un mes para
able to respond and defend myself it could be
poder contestar y defenderme puede ser
the end of sanctuary yes it could be the
el final de santuario sí puede ser el
end of a time of freedom for me
final de un tiempo en libertad mío
too it could cost me money it is going to
también puede que me cueste dinero me va
cost me a lot of money this eh it could
a costar mucho dinero esto eh puede que
collaterally affect my children
afecte colateralmente a mis hijos
totally because I am the foundation
totalmente porque yo soy el fundamento
of the family I am the one who supports the
de la familia Yo soy el que mantiene la
family and at the end of the day eh all of this
familia y al final del día eh todo esto
is going to harm many more beings both
va a dañar a bastante más seres tanto
human and non-human than they
humanos como no humanos de lo que se
thought it seems to me a real ruin
pensaban me parece una auténtica ruine
something very
algo muy
ruinous yes I am not going to  forgive never I
ruínas sí que no voy a perdonar jamás yo
am not at war I am not an enemy of
no estoy en guerra yo no soy enemigo de
anyone but when you do things that
nadie pero cuando tú ya haces cosas que
affect your children directly
afectan a tus hijos directamente
judicially
judicialmente
and in their life already on a very personal level
y en su vida ya a nivel eh muy personal
eh I am very sorry that it cannot
eh Lo siento mucho por ahí no se puede
happen I could leave the country and get rid of
pasar me podía ir del país y librarme de
everything yes I am going to leave the animals here
todo sí voy a dejar a los animales aquí
alone no they will take me out of here to
solos no a mí me sacarán de aquí para la
jail or they will take me to the airport
cárcel o me sacarán para el aeropuerto
But I am not going to leave the animals
Pero yo a los animales no los voy a
here alone because it is my
dejar aquí solos porque es mi
responsibility to be here until the
responsabilidad el estar aquí hasta el
day they arrest me take me to
día que me detengan me lleven a la
jail or until the day eh they take me out
cárcel o hasta el día eh que me saquen
of the country and deport me and they don't let me
del país y me deporten y no me dejen
come back for 20 years that is what they are looking for
volver en 20 años eso es lo que buscan
that is what they will possibly get but
eso es lo que posiblemente consigan pero
I believe that in life what is fair
yo creo que en la vida lo que es justo
is fair and whoever does things with
es justo y el que hace las cosas con
malice sooner or later will
maldad tarde o temprano pues pues se
meet their match Did you
encontrará con la horma de su zapato de
see that laser supports Fran's ex
Ya viste que láser apoya la ex de Fran
Yes yes we have been seeing it before it is what is
Sí sí lo hemos estado viendo antes es lo
expected agreement it is what was
que se espera acuerdo es lo que se
expected eh I could ask for
esperaba eh Yo podría pedir daños y
damages I could ask for many things but
perjuicios podía pedir muchas cosas pero
the funny thing is that that  person that I
lo curioso es que esa persona que que yo
took to more than 15
la llevé a más de 15 centros de
rehabilitation centers hospitals treatments
rehabilitación hospitales tratamientos
that for 6 years and something in jail I
que durante 6 años y algo en la cárcel
took care of so that she was in the best part
cuidé de que estuviera en la mejor parte
of jail paying and spending money
de la cárcel pagando y gastando dinero
That person that I went to every [ __ ]
Esa persona que yo iba todas las [__]
early morning to bring her food That person
madrugadas a llevarle comida Esa persona
that I took care of the family and we didn't move
que yo cuidé la familia y no nos movimos
from Thailand Because they put her
de Tailandia Porque a ella la metieron
in jail for her own crime that
en la cárcel por su propio delito esa
person that I for more than 20 years I have taken
persona que yo durante más de 20 años he
care of I have somehow maintained and I have
cuidado He de alguna manera mantenido y
never left alone or aside or
nunca he dejado sola ni de lado ni
apart or in [ __ ] that person that
apartada ni en la [__] esa persona que
I managed to get out of jail wants to
Yo conseguí sacar de la cárcel quiere
put me in jail right now how
meterme en la cárcel ahora mismo qué
strong eh how heavy eh I mean,
fuerte eh qué heavy eh o sea ya lo de
taking away the sanctuary was
quitarle el santuario era
like you know it was like fabric it was like your
como sabes era como tela era como tu
match no no more I mean after everything
match no ya no O sea después de todo lo
that he has given you in life and everything that he
que te ha dado en la vida y todo lo que
has done for you and it was already like t much to
ha hecho por ti e ya era como t much
take and want to put him in jail what
[__] y querer meterlo en la cárcel qué
level No how heavy very crazy very crazy very crazy
nivel No qué heavy muy loco muy loco muy
the truth is I hope it turns out well
loco la verdad espero que salga bien
I hope it turns out well
Espero que salga bien
[Music]
[Música]